无法摆脱工作的压力？
Can't get the monkey off your back?
那就来一杯…
Then put it in your mouth...
…猴子乐(原意为恶作剧)啤酒吧
... with Monkeyshine Beer!
喝一口猴子乐
Get it,monkey
Get it,get it,monkey
猴子乐…
Monkey,monkey
猴子乐啤酒
Monkeyshine Beer.
因为外面是一片丛林
Because it's a jungle out there!
那个广告总是让我很难过
That commercial always makes me so sad.
但是那个家伙一开啤酒 女人就拥上来了…
But then the guy opens his beer and girls run at him...
…所以最后一切还好的
...so everything works out okay.
我的意思是 那只猴子让我想到了马修
I meant because the monkey reminds me of Marcel.
我看得出来
I can see that.
它们都有棕色的大眼睛 还有鼓鼓的小下巴
Because they both have those big brown eyes and the little pouty chin.
而且它们都是猴子
And the fact that they're both monkeys?
有时候我怀疑我是不是做错了 不应该把它送走
I wonder if I did the right thing,giving him away.
你必须这么做 它看到什么东西都要上
Ross,you had to. He was humping everything in sight.
我的马里布芭比娃娃 结婚不能穿纯洁的白纱了
My Malibu Barbie will no longer be wearing white to her wedding.
记得有时它会跟你们借帽子…
Remember when he'd borrow your hat...
…等你要回来的时候里面会有 小小的猴子“葡萄干”？
...and when you got it back,there'd be monkey raisins in it?
它喜欢开这个玩笑
He loved that joke
它干的就叫好玩 如果我对我老板这么做的话…
When he did it,it was funny. When I did it to my boss's hat....
突然就变成了我的严重的“态度问题”
Suddenly,I had this big "attitude problem."
六人行 第2季 第12-13集 超级碗比赛之后
The One With the Super Bowl
你们看，猜我有什么？
Hey,check it out! Guess what I got?
押韵？
Rhythm?
不是，第一封影迷信
No. My first fan mail!
亲爱的雷莫瑞医生：
"Dear Dr. Ramoray:
我爱你，为了得到你 我可以不惜一切
I love you and would do anything to have you."
“你不神秘的仰慕者 艾瑞克福特”
My gosh! "Your not-so-secret admirer,Erika Ford."
等一下
Oh,wait.
：“附注：随函附上了 我十四根的睫毛”
"P.S. Enclosed,please find 14 of my eyelashes."
在疯子的世界里 那就表示你结婚了
In Crazy World,that means you're married.
这不是寄到“我们的日子”的 这是直接送到你家去
It's not addressed to Days Of Our Lives. This came to your apartment.
她去过我们的大楼
She was in our building.
我的天啊
Oh,my God.
我有我自己的变态影迷了
I got my very own stalker!
你真走运，我只能跟一群工作上的家伙分享
You' re so lucky.I have to share with guys at work.
还记得我们讨论过好事坏事吗，这是件坏事
Remember we talked about "good thing,bad thing"?. This is a bad thing.
-嘿，大家 -嘿
-Hey, guys.-Hey.
你上哪儿去了？
Where are you off to?
因为洛杉矶有一个古生物学研讨会
There's a paleontology conference in L.A.
我会去，然后开车到动物园 给马修一个惊喜
So I figured I'd go and drive down to the zoo and surprise Marcel.
我想它会很惊喜的 直到它发现它是猴子…
He will be surprised. Till he realizes he's a monkey...
…它根本就没办法有那种情绪
...and isn't capable of that emotion.
菲比，那个可爱的家伙又来了
Phoebe? That really cute guy is here again.
各位…
Okay,so everyone...
…假装我在讲故事给你们听 故事非常的好笑
... pretend I'm telling you a story and it's really funny.
所以大家要笑
So everyone just laugh. Now!
我知道
I know,I know!
我叫罗伯杜南
I'm Rob Donan.
罗伯杜南
Hi,Rob Donan.
我对音乐一窍不通 不过我觉得你非常棒
I don't know anything about music,but I think you're really great.
我在替市里的儿童图书馆 安排艺人的演出
Anyway,I schedule performers for children's libraries.
我在想，你有没有想过 为小孩子演唱你的歌呢？
And I was thinking,have you thought about playing your songs for kids?
我好想要孩子…
I would love to have kids...
听我…听我演唱 我为他们写的歌
...hear me play the songs that I will write for them.
我们今天晚饭做什么？
What do we do for dinner?
我们可以留在家里吃自己啊
We could cook for ourselves.
我是艾瑞克
It's Erika.
上帝啊，变态影迷
My God. The stalker!
没关系，门没关
Never mind. It's open.
对，用平底锅打她是个好主意
Hitting her with a frying pan is a good idea.
不过，我们应该想点别的 以防她不是卡通人物
But we want a backup plan,just in case she isn't a cartoon!
离开这里
Let's get out of here!
偏挑这个时候不在
The one time they're not home!
我们走时 在楼梯上碰到的时候…
We'll leave. When we pass her...
…她不会知道是我 因为我们没有见过啊
...she won't know me,because we never met!
那是收音机明星逃避变态的方法
That's how radio stars escape stalkers!
她来了
She's coming!
是我
It's me.
就这样了，我们就这样死的
This is it. This is how we're gonna die.
预备好了？
You ready?
等等…
Wait,wait,wait!
波姬小丝（影星）
Brooke Shields
艾瑞克
Erika!
盖勒先生？ 是，嗨
-Mr. Geller? -Yes,hi.
迪恩利浦森，我是动物园的管理员
Dean Lipson,zoo administrator.
听说你有个问题，是不是？
You had a question?
我似乎找不到我去年捐的猴子 它是一只卷尾猴…
I can't find the monkey I donated last year. He's a capuchin...
…它的名字叫做马修？
...answers to the name Marcel?
我恐怕有个坏消息要告诉你
I'm afraid I have some bad news.
马修它已经过世了
Marcel has passed on.
天哪，怎么会呢？
Oh,my God. What happened?
它生病了，然后它病得很重…
He got sick,and then he got sicker...
…然后它突然好了一点
...and then he got a little better.
然后就死了
But then he died.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this!
很抱歉，盖勒先生 你也知道嘛，俗话说：
I'm sorry,Mr. Geller. But you know,there's an old saying:
“猴子难免一死”
"Sometimes monkeys die."
不是很好的俗语…
It's not a great saying...
…用在今天却很贴切
... but it certainly is fitting today.
那应该有人通知我才对呀 对不起
-Someone should've called me. -I'm sorry.
我知道这不能够让它复活…
Look,I know this can't bring him back...
…这是我一点心意，请收下
... but here,it's just a gesture.
动物园礼券？
Zoo dollars?
对，四点请过来看一看鸟的表演 金刚鹦鹉戴帽子
Yes,and come see the bird show at 4. The macaws wear hats.
你的猴子没死的话会可爱多了
It's a lot cuter if your monkey hasn't just died.
我知道
I know.
真不敢相信 乔伊去跟他的变态影迷吃饭
I can't believe Joey's having lunch with his stalker!
她长得怎么样？
What is she like?
你还记得“危情十日” 里面的凯西贝茨吗？
You remember Kathy Bates in Misery?
她长得跟她完全相反
Well,she looks the exact opposite of that.
她不是疯子吗？
And she's not crazy?
不，她只是神经有问题
Oh,no,no. She's a total whack-job.
她以为乔伊真的是德瑞克雷莫瑞医生
She thinks that Joey is actually Dr. Drake Ramoray.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
然后他还要去跟她约会？
And he's going out with her?
他不能这么做的
He cannot pursue this.
就因为这个女人以为她可以 在她的客厅魔盒里面看乔伊…
Just because this woman sees Joey through the magical box...
…并不表示她就不是人啊
...in her living room doesn't mean she's not a person.
我是说，她应该得到快乐 也应该得到爱呀
Does she not deserve happiness? Does she not deserve love?
你们看我干什么？ 想上那个疯子的是乔伊耶
Why are you looking at me? He's the one who wants to boff the maniac!
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
不，我只是很紧张
No. I'm just nervous.
如果我幻想他们只穿内衣…
Maybe if I just picture them all in their underwear....
不，那个主意不好 上个家伙就是那样被开除的
That's not a good idea. That's the reason the last guy got fired.
我只是…我习惯为大人演唱
I'm used to playing for grownups.
大人只是… 边喝咖啡边做他们大人做的事
Grownups drink their coffee and do their grownup thing.
小孩呢…
And kids...
…会专心听
...Iisten.
我觉得这个责任好重大
It's just a huge responsibility.
怎么了？
What?
你要亲我吗？
Are you gonna kiss me?
我正在考虑
I was thinking about it.
那好，好耶，咱们来些音乐
Alrighty! Let's play some tunes!
我们找地方坐吧，钱德
Let's go find our seats.Chandler?.
等一下
Hold on a second.
他认为他可以
He thinks he can.
哦，搞什么
Oh, what the hell?.
他可以
He can.
各位，我是菲比 菲比
-Hi,everybody. I'm Phoebe. -Hi,Phoebe!
现在我要唱一首 关于祖父母的歌
I'm gonna play some songs about grandparents,okay?
奶奶走到哪里都大受欢迎
Now Grandma's a person Who everyone likes
她送你火车跟一辆闪亮的自行车
She bought you a train And a bright shiny bike
但最近她不再来共进晚餐
But lately she hasn't Been coming to dinner
上回你看到她时 她看起来瘦多了
And last time you saw her She looked so much thinner
你妈跟你爸说她搬去秘鲁
Now your mom and your dad said She moved to Peru
事实上她死了，有一天你也会
But the truth is she died And someday you will too
我要香烤鲑鱼
I'll have the grilled salmon.
这位医生要意大利调味饭
And the doctor will have the risotto
德瑞克，这真是太好了 是啊，没错
-Oh,Drake,isn't it amazing? -Yeah,it is.
怎么了？
What?
现在我们轻松地坐在这儿…
Well,here we sit,devil-may-care...
…但不久前 你还在重注西蒙的脊髓
...and a while ago you were reattaching Simone's spinal cord.
是啊，那很复杂
That was a tricky one.
事实上…
In reality...
…那个手术要花上十几个钟头 可是他们只播了两分钟而已
...that operation takes 10 hours. But they only showed it for 2 minutes.
“他们”是谁？
Who's "they"?
没有啦
No one.
德瑞克，你真有才华 让我看看那双手
Drake,you are so talented. Let me see those hands.
这双美丽的手
Oh,these hands,these beautiful hands.
真想吃掉它们
I could just eat them.
但我不会
But I won't.
不然我的手表一定会掉下来
Otherwise my watch would fall off.
不，说真的
No,seriously.
这双…
These hands...
…救人无数，创造奇迹的手
...these miracle,magical,life-giving hands.
只要靠近，抚摸 或许甚至舔一只就好了
Just to be near them,touch them,maybe even lick one?
好吧，一只就好了
All right. Just one.
你很行耶
You're good at that.
天哪，来人哪，他噎住了
Oh,my God! Someone! He's choking!
这里有没有医生？
Is anyone here a doctor?
塞林镇最好的医生就在这儿
Yes,the best doctor in Salem!
德瑞克雷莫瑞医生
Dr. Drake Ramoray!
你十五分钟之后到夜行馆等我
Meet me in the nocturnal house in 15 minutes.
嗨， 我不喜欢跟别的男人那样
Hey,look. I don't really enjoy being with other men that way.
要动物园礼券吗？
But,zoo dollars?
我要告诉你有关你猴子的事
It's about your monkey!
它还没死
It's alive.
我不懂，你为什么不救他？
I don't understand. Why didn't you help that man?
因为我是神经外科医生…
Because I'm a neurosurgeon...
…他显然是患了…
...and that was clearly a case of...
…“食道阻塞症”
... "foodal chokage."
好吧，听着 我要坦白一件事…
I gotta tell you something
你什么都不用告诉我
You don't have to tell me anything.
你不用向我解释什么
You don't have to explain yourself to me.
我算什么啊竟然敢怀疑伟大的德瑞克雷莫瑞医生
Who am I to question the great Dr. Drake Ramoray?
能接近你，我就该满足了
I should be happy to be near you.
嘿，我…
Hey,l
嘿什么？
Hey what?
就那样，只是嘿
That's it. Just hey!
像结束了一首舞那样，嘿！
Like at the end of a dance. Hey!
有一天你们会长大
There'll be times when you get older
你们会想跟别人上床
When you'll want to sleep with people
只为搏得他们欢心 但不要这么做
Just to make them like you But don't!
因为…
'Cause...
…那是另一件…
... that's another thing...
…你不要做的事 一起来
... that you don't wanna do Everybody!
那是另一件你不要做的事
That's another thing That you don't wanna do
太棒了 很有教育性
-Excellent! -Very informative!
一点也不会不恰当
Not at all inappropriate!
谢谢各位光临 后面有饼干要送给你们
Thank you for coming,everybody! There are cookies in the back.
真是棒透了
That was great.
孩子们爱死你了
The kids loved you.
对呀，我酷毙了
Yea! I rock!
你知道为什么吗？ 因为你说实话
And you know why? Because you told the truth.
从来没有人对小孩子说实话
Nobody ever tells kids the truth.
你真是了得
You were incredible!
但…？
But...?
你怎么知道还有“但…”？ 这种事情逃不过我的
-How'd you know there was a "but"? -I sense these things.
不是“但是”就是奉承话
It was either "but" or "butter."
我想问题是有些父母…
The thing is,I think some of the parents...
…会希望你多唱一点…
...they were hoping that...
…农场动物那类的歌曲
...you'd play more songs about barnyard animals.
这个我办得到啊
I can do that.
真的？
Really?
因为那样子会非常棒
Because that would be fantastic!
怎么？你要亲我吗？
What? You wanna kiss me?
我正在考虑
I'm thinking about it.
如果我有借书卡，我能借走你吗
If I get a library card,can I take you out some time?
怎么？我没工作
What?I'm unemployed
蝙蝠
The bat.
黑暗世界的大使
Ambassador of darkness.
像一只插翅的信差 冲出了巢穴
Flitting out of his cave like a winged messenger.
死神之舞的盲目幽灵
Sightless specter of the macabre.
兄弟，我的猴子呢？
Buddy,my monkey?
对了…
Oh,yeah,right.
在几个月前…
There was a break-in...
…这里被洗劫，内贼干的
...a few months back. Inside job.
你的猴子被偷了
Your monkey was taken.
还有一只雪鹭，一只两脚趾的树懒
Along with a snowy egret,a two-toed sloth...
还有礼品店的三件运动衫
...and three sweatshirts from the zoo gift shop.
我的天哪 可是动物园说我的猴子死了
The zoo told me that my monkey was dead!
动物园
The zoo!
你相信 动物园说的每一件事吗？
You believe everything the zoo tells you?
动物园只是告诉过我这一件事
That's the only thing the zoo's ever told me.
他们当然会说它死了 他们害怕消息传出去会不好看
Of course they'll say that! They don't want the bad publicity.
他们掩饰得密不透风
It's all a great big cover-up.
你知道这件事情 牵涉到多高层吗？
Do you have any idea how high up this thing goes?
那个利浦森先生？
That guy Lipson?
利浦森先生知道？
Lipson knows?
-谁还知道？-我只认识利浦森
-Who else knows?.-I only know Lipson.
利浦森先生知道，是吗？
Lipson knows,huh?
你好，负鼠先生
Hello,Mr. Possum.
树上的谜团 上下颠倒的夜之民
Enigma of the trees,upside-down denizen of the night.
正在嘲弄着地心引力… 兄弟，我的猴子呢？
-Taunting gravity -Buddy,my monkey. My monkey?
道上的传闻…
Word on the street
当我说“道上”的时候 我指的是园里的游园道路
When I say "street," I mean those pretend streets here at the zoo.
当然了
Of course.
你的猴子有了新职业了…
Your monkey found a new career...
…往娱乐界发展去了 我只知道这一些
...in the entertainment field. That's all I know.
真是令人难以置信
This is unbelievable!
好了，这个消息 对你值多少钱啊，朋友？
So what is this information worth to you,my friend?
你是暗示我要贿赂你吗？
Are you trying to get me to bribe you?
或许吧
Maybe.
可是你都已经告诉我了
But you already told me everything.
你们看
Check it out.
马修就是 啤酒乐广告里的那只猴子
He actually is the Monkeyshine monkey!
那你打算怎么办？
What'll you do?
我要打电话给那家啤酒厂 问他们它在哪里啊
I'm gonna call the beer company and try to find him.
我丢了我的健壮驮马时就是这么做的
That's what I did when I lost my Clydesdales.
你们好
Okay,hi again!
菲比好
Hi,Phoebe!
今天我们要先唱一些 关于农场动物的歌曲
Today,we're gonna start with some songs about barnyard animals.
草地上的牛说哞
Oh,the cow in the meadow goes "moo"
农夫在敲它的头 把它绞成肉酱
Then the farmer hits him And grinds him up
汉堡就是这样来的
And that's how we get hamburgers
现在…鸡
Now chickens!
德瑞克，你是唯一救得了她的人
Only you who can save her,Drake!
该死，我是医生，我不是神
Damn it! I'm a doctor. I'm not God!
我的信仰就是这样被推翻了的
There goes my whole belief system.
是艾瑞克
It's Erika.
老天，快，关掉电视
Quick! Shut off the TV.
不，我要看结果
I wanna see what happens!
我救莱丝莉脱离昏迷状态 然后我们亲热
I get Leslie out of the coma then we make out.
怎么可能？你刚才亲了莎宾娜
How can that be? You were kissing Sabrina!
瑞秋，那只是乔伊是神经外科医生的世界
Rachel,it's a world where Joey is a neurosurgeon.
艾瑞克，请进
Hey,Erika. Come in.
你怎么这么快就到了？ 我刚刚还在塞林看到你
How did you get here so fast? I just saw you in Salem.
对，他们用…直升机送我
Right,they choppered me in.
什么事？
What's up?
还有一场小派对
You're having a little party too!
她在吗？ 谁啊？
-ls she here? -Who?
莎宾娜，你们的事我全知道了
Sabrina. I know about you two!
我看到你们两个 在医生休息室里接吻
I saw you today,kissing in the doctor's lounge.
不是你想的那样子啦，那是…
It's not what you think
你说你心里只有我
You told me I was the only one!
好，听着，够了
All right,look. That's it.
我想我们不该再见面了
We shouldn't see each other anymore.
我知道我很久以前 就应该告诉你了…
I should have told you a long time ago...
…我并不是德瑞克雷莫瑞医生
... but I am not Drake Ramoray.
我连医生都不是，我是个演员 我只是假装我是医生而已
I'm not even a doctor. I'm an actor. I just pretend to be a doctor.
天哪，那医院的人 知道这件事情吗？
Oh,my God! Do the people at the hospital know?
你们谁来帮帮忙，好不好？
Somebody wanna help me out here?
我知道…
Oh,I know! I know!
我在哪里？
Where am I?
大学的附设医院…
University Hospital...
…你已经在这里度过十八年了
... where you've been for the last 18 years.
你怎么会在两个地方？
How can you be here and there?
因为那是电视节目
Because it's a TV show!
德瑞克，你到底要说什么？
What are you getting at?
长相很漂亮，但是神志不清
Nice girl. Not great with concepts.
我不是德瑞克
I'm not Drake!
没错 他不是德瑞克，他是…
That's right! He's not Drake. He's...
…汉斯雷莫瑞，德瑞克邪恶的双胞胎兄弟
... Hans Ramoray,Drake's evil twin!
真的吗？
Is this true?
是真的
Yes! Yes,it is true!
我之所以知道是因为…
And I know this...
…他假装他是德瑞克 来…来骗我上床
... because he pretended to be Drake to sleep with me!
并且他告诉我他要带我私奔
And then he told me he would run away with me!
他骗我
And he didn't!
而且你马桶盖没有放下来 你这个浑蛋
And you left the toilet seat up,you bastard!
这些都是真的吗？
Is all this true?
是，恐怕是真的了
Yes,I'm afraid it is.
我根本配不上你，艾瑞克
You deserve much better than me.
你应该跟真正的德瑞克在一起 你爱上的人是他
You deserve to be with the real Drake. He's the one you fell in love with.
去塞林吧，去找他
Go to Salem. Find him!
他才是你的
He's the guy for you!
汉斯
Oh,Hans!
汉斯？
Hans?
汉斯！
Hans!
邪恶的双胞胎
Yo,evil twin!
对，再见，艾瑞克
Right. Goodbye,Erika.
祝你在塞林一切顺利
Good luck in Salem.
保重了
Take care.
我永远不会忘记你的，汉斯
I'll never forget you,Hans.
刚才是谁向我泼水！
All right. The people who threw the water!
我们只是想帮你
Helping you out!
开除？
Fired?
为什么？
Why?
有很多父母向图书馆的 董事会投诉…
The library board got a lot of complaints from parents...
…你歌词里的一些内容有问题
...about the stuff in your songs.
我真不敢相信，图书馆？
I can't believe it!The library？
-书籍，自由演讲，报纸 -我知道
-Books. Free speech.Newspapers on sticks.-I know.
-孩子们呢？难道说你没有告诉董事会孩子们想听实话吗？-没
-And the kids?Did you tell your board that the kids want to hear the truth?-No
我懂了
I see.
或许如果你只是唱一些 一般的儿歌
Maybe if you just played some regular kiddy songs?
不，你要…我当什么呢？
What do you want me to be? Like some...
…当一只愚蠢的 紫色大恐龙吗？
...stupid,big,like,purple dinosaur?
我又没说你必须当巴尼
You don't have to be Barney.
巴尼是谁啊？
Who's Barney?
你们不会相信的
You'll never believe it.
-让我猜猜 -什么？
-Let me guess.-What?.
一些胖子真的跳下来了？
Some Weebles actually do fall down?.
一块布只救了七个人？你猜到了什么？
A stitch in time now only saves seven?What do you got?.
那么…
Well...
算了
... never mind.
什么 什么
What?. What?.
我是追查马修追查到这个的 现在它很健康也很快乐…
I tracked down Marcel and get this. He's healthy,he's happy...
…它在纽约拍“极度恐慌II 病毒肆虐曼哈顿”
...and he's in New York filming Outbreak 2: The Virus Takes Manhattan.
你骗人
You're kidding!
简直不可思议 我知道
-This is amazing! -I know.
我才终于混上电视 这猴子开始拍电影了
I finally get a part on TV,and the monkey's making movies.
瑞秋，我好了
Rachel,I'm ready.
抱歉，那个说实话的唱歌小姐在这里吗？
Excuse me. Is this where the singing lady is,who tells the truth?
对呀，我猜那就是我
I guess that's me.
她在这里
She's here!
有时男人爱女人
Sometimes men love women
有时男人爱男人
Sometimes men love men
然后还有双性恋
Then there are bisexuals
虽然有些说他们在骗自己
Though some just say They're kidding themselves
真是令人兴奋 我都快一年没见到我的猴子了
This is exciting! I haven't seen my monkey in a year.
你洗澡从来不往下看吗？
What,you never look down in the shower?
我连说个“猴子是阴茎”的笑话都不可以吗？
I'm not allowed to make one joke in the "monkey is penis" genre?
好了，好了
Back up,please.
各位，往后退
Back up. Come on.
打扰了 我们在哪里能找到猴子？
Excuse me. Where can we find the monkey?
抱歉，各位 这场戏不对外开放
I'm sorry. It's a closed set.
对不起，你不了解 我…我是它的朋友
I'm sorry,you don't understand. I'm a friend of his.
我们…我们以前住在一起的
We used to live together.
我跟费利佩（《海豚的故事》中的海豚）还曾在波克若山分租公寓呢
And I have a time share in the Poconos with Flipper.
罗斯，它在那里
There he is!
兄弟
Hey! Buddy!
马修…
Marcel! Marcel!
在丛林里
In the jungle
偌大的丛林
The mighty jungle
今夜狮子睡着了
The lion sleeps tonight
在丛林里，偌大的丛林
In the jungle The mighty jungle
今夜狮子睡着了
The lion sleeps tonight
抱歉，各位，这片场…
Excuse me,this is a
不对外，我们知道 我们是猴子的朋友
Closed set. We know. But we're friends with the monkey.
早安
Good morning.
伙计，你看我带谁来了
Look who I brought!
是你的老朋友耶，小象哈瑞
Your old friend,Harry Elafonte!
老兄，火气真大！
Whoa,dude. Burn!
我不懂
I don't get it.
它昨天好像很高兴看到我
He seemed so happy to see me yesterday.
别放在心上，它近来压力很大 你知道，主演一部电影
Don't take it personal. He's under pressure,starring in a movie and all.
马修现在到底有多大牌呀？
How big of a star is Marcel?
用人来比啊，我说像…
In human terms? I'd say...